### Contact

+919508038514 (Mobile) prashantsavior@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ prashantkumardey (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Cyber-security
Ethical Hacking
Web Development

## Languages

English (Full Professional)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
Bengali (Native or Bilingual)
Oriya (Limited Working)
French (Elementary)

## Certifications

Cryptography

Penetration Testing and Ethical Hacking

#### **Publications**

Classical Cryptography: The History of Ciphers

CRYPTOGRAPHICALLY USE OF CAESAR CIPHER TECHNIQUE IN PASSWORD MANAGING AND SECURITY SYSTEM

# **Prashant Kumar Dey**

Changing lives of students using technology. Delhi, India

# Summary

Prashant is on a mission to teach at least 1 million students in the next 3 years. He is a cybersecurity expert holding a master's degree from EURECOM. He has experience working with various startups, new technologies, and MNC like BMW, Google WebRTC in France, Singapore, India and the culture of startups has boosted his carrier at a very small amount of time. The technical knowledge obtained through his degree helped him in building DIYguru, FindMeMentor, and Timoo. Working with startups has helped him even to look into the business side of the product that has been developed and understand the client's requirements.

The startup ecosystem has created a greater impact and the postgraduate diploma course at the Department of Management Science, IIT Delhi in Entrepreneurship has led to the birth of FindMeMentor.com which is an Al-enabled edtech marketplace where anyone can come, teach online, and earn money. Al helps in understanding the engagement of students and then work towards elevating the performance of students.

# Experience

AtharvaAl Co-Founder 2021 - Present (3 years) India

Deep Tech research-based organization using technologies like Blockchain, Al/ML, AR/VR, etc. to create products for the masses.

Current Product: https://feedo.one/

Realtime feedback application. Feedback are given to improve the quality of users communication skill.

Research and Development:

Creating AI based model to give unbiased feedback to trainers/speakers after their sessions. Model analyzes Voice, Facial Expression and Texts used.

## Technical Experience:

As a technical co-founder, we created Feedo which gives feedback to users in their communication on real time basis. Feedo is a cross platform application developed using ElectronJS, backend uses Flask. The term "MLOps" is quite used among the deployment team. Deployment is on AWS.

#### Business Side:

Still on development stage.

#### Leadership Role:

Continuous interaction and providing updates to the investors, stakeholders, etc.

## Hero Vired

Specialist

November 2021 - Present (2 years 9 months)

New Delhi, Delhi, India

#### Subject Matter Expert of:

- Frontend Development (HTML, CSS, JS)
- Backend Development (Flask, Django)
- DevOps (Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, GCP, Azure)
- Databases (Mongo, MySQL, PostgreSQL)
- Frameworks (Rails, Django, Angular)
- Stacks (MEAN, MERN, LAMP, Ruby based Stack, Python based Stack)
- Security (Major focused on Web Security)
- General Topics (Linux, Python, Agile, etc.)

#### Activity:

- Take live classes
- Take doubt clearing sessions
- Create content and syllabus for the courses

Infosec United
Chief Technology Officer
February 2021 - Present (3 years 6 months)

Infosec united (formerly called Hacking the people) is a community to help people with cybersecurity queries. It's a not-for-profit community. As CTO, I am responsible for:

- 1. Development of community platforms and leading open source projects.
- 2. Solving cybersecurity queries.
- 3. Taking free classes on cybersecurity.

Join our community: https://join.slack.com/t/hackingthepeople/shared\_invite/zt-reeukd1w-YqyVC5dMsoY90aaMmhXOrA

IU International University of Applied Sciences Visiting Faculty January 2022 - September 2022 (9 months) Germany

Taking classes for cybersecurity master's students in collaboration with Upgrad.

#### Job Role:

- Creating courses on cybersecurity
- Taking classes on "Cryptography"
- Helping students with projects

## upGrad

Senior Subject Matter Expert January 2021 - September 2022 (1 year 9 months) Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

As a subject matter expert for "Cybersecurity Course", my job role is:

- Create syllabus for the cybersecurity.
- Record videos for cybersecurity courses.
- Take live classes on various topics of cybersecurity.
- Take live small group sessions (SGC)
- Take 1:1 mentorship call with learners.
- Career Coaching where helping learners in excelling their career in cybersecurity.

Find Me Mentor
Chief Executive Officer
November 2019 - October 2021 (2 years)
New Delhi Area, India

As a co-founder and CEO of FindMeMentor, our aim was to provide a SAAS based edtech product for universities, schools, etc. to conduct classes. FindMeMentor has an inbuilt live class feature, along with the recorded class.

### Technical Experience:

As a technical co-founder, I undertook the responsibility of developing the website which used Angular for frontend, Postgres as database and Django for backend. Video calling feature used WebRTC as major technology. Application was deployed on AWS using Amazon EKS.

## Business Experience:

Onboarded 3 universities and schools who conducted live classes from our platform. A total of 6500 students had taken live classes with over 2500 hours of classes being conducted from FindMeMentor platform during COVID-19 wave.

## Closing Down:

The ease of COVID restrictions (colleges, schools reopening), increasing competition (new startups coming at this space while giants like zoom, meet, teams providing services at cheaper rates), we closed down the operations.

# Yuwee Information Security Advisor May 2020 - April 2021 (1 year) Singapore, Singapore

# Timoo Chief Executive Officer September 2018 - 2020 (2 years) Singapore

Timoo is a travel dating/meetup website which was founded at Singapore. The aim of Timoo is to make traveling easy and fun and at the same time meet new people.

Timoo is not a traditional dating website. It gives you opportunity to find dates while traveling together.

If you are not interested in dating but interested in meeting new people, we got you covered for that. Just use the friends trip to create trip and find friends.

## DIYguru 2 years 2 months

## Chief Technology Officer

February 2018 - October 2019 (1 year 9 months)

New Delhi Area, India

My role as a chief technical officer is:

- \* To maintain the website in the good health and keep on adding new features, improve the UI/UX of the website according to the user demand.
- \* Creating platforms for managing students using LAMP and MERN stack. Deployments were majorly on Microsoft Azure and GCP.
- \* Strategic development of the new features like "Light board video tutorials" (first time in India).
- \* Partnering with creators to create new video courses especially related with the computer science
- \* Hiring interns and employees to be part of the technical team
- \* Business development and Partnering with the companies around the globe.

## **Project Manager**

September 2017 - January 2018 (5 months)

New Delhi Area, India

The startups usually face a cash crunch and in order to keep up with the revenue of the startup, they find various ways to keep up with the revenue, DIYguru faced similar situation and so it also provided IT consulting to small scale business including the digital marketing, creating websites and small scale application. My role as the Project Manager was to complete the projects and keep up with the clients expectation. Also, in some cases I have to hire some freelancer or developers (on contract basis) to keep up with the work rate.

## BMW Forschung und Technik

**Project Manager** 

November 2018 - March 2019 (5 months)

Nice Area, France

Designing security architecture of M2M modules used in various vehicles. Finding out vulnerability in APIs and their connection with end applications and devices.

## Google

8 months

Security Researcher

September 2018 - October 2018 (2 months)

Philippines

Working with small and medium sized businesses in creating secured RTC enabled applications using google APIs. Providing customer support to business.

Engineer Intern March 2018 - September 2018 (7 months) Singapore

Working on Google backed WebRTC.

The topic was "Implementing Double Encryption in WebRTC which is known as PERC".

WebRTC is a free, open project that provides browsers and mobile applications with Real-Time Communications (RTC) capabilities via simple APIs. WebRTC is used by Google Hangout, Google Meet, Google Duo, Facebook Messenger, Discord, etc.

My job responsibility:

- \* Understanding and implementing the PERC double encryption on the Webrtc
- \* Implement the mutual authentication on the sample client and the server
- \* Use Qt to make a cross platform application (Windows, Mac, iOS, Android) which will have a video calling feature using the PERC implementation and the mutual authentication with the SFU. This is the first time when Qt was used with webrtc.
- \* Write the documentation on Qt build for Webrtc on Android and iOS

Skills Used: C++, Webrtc, Python, NodeJS, Cmake, Qt, Linux, Windows, Android, iOS, Mac, Microsoft Word, Git

InternetGenX | The Next Generation Internet Co-Founder August 2014 - November 2017 (3 years 4 months) New Delhi Area, India

InternetGenx is an IT consulting startup.

- \* Create new business.
- \* Involve with the development team and help them with the website development
- \* Check the security of the websites and application made
- \* Planning and writing documentation on the project

Skills Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, Linux, Windows, Android, GDB, Burp Suite, IDA Pro.

KIIT Student Activity Centre | KSAC 1 year 9 months

Coordinator (KIIT Web Development Society) August 2015 - April 2016 (9 months) Bhubaneshwar Area, India

on "Cyber Security" and "Web Development".

Being a coordinator of Konnexion Society of KIIT University involves undertaking various student projects like making websites of various events organised in KIIT University, many research project, also it involves teaching to student on various aspects of Information Technology which are usually not taught in university syllabus programs. I was responsible for teaching student

Assistant Coordinator (KIIT Web Development Society) August 2014 - July 2015 (1 year)

As an assistant coordinator, I was to train student with various courses like Web Development, Cyber Security (Ethical Hacking). Along with this I was also given the responsible for the development of websites for the various events organised in KIIT University.

# Education

#### **EURECOM**

Master's degree, Digital Security (2016 - 2018)

Department of Management Studies, IIT Delhi
Post Masters Certification Course, Entrepreneurship (2019)

Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology
Bachelor of Technology (BTech), Electronics and Communications
Engineering · (2012 - 2016)

Millia Convent English Medium School Undergraduate, Science (2010 - 2012)

Millia Convent English Medium School

Matriculation, Science, Mathematics, Social Science, English and

Sanskrit · (2009 - 2010)